-You swear it?
-CATELYN: By the mother.
My son has no interest in the Iron Throne.
Then I see no reason for hostility between us.
Your son can go on
calling himself King in the North.
The Starks will have dominion
over all lands north of Moat Cailin.
provided he swears me an oath of fealty.
And the wording of this oath?
The same Ned Stark swore
to Robert 18 years ago.
Cat. their friendship held
the kingdoms together.
And in return for my son's loyalty?
In the morning. I'll destroy my brother's army.
When that's done.
Baratheon and Stark will fight
their common enemy together.
as they have done many times before.
Our two houses have always been close.
which is why I am begging you
to reconsider this battle.
Negotiate a peace with your brother.
Negotiate with Stannis? (CHUCKLES)
You heard him out there.
I'd have better luck debating the wind.
Please bring my terms to your son.
I believe we are natural allies.
I hope he feels the same.
Together we could end this war in a fortnight.
(WIND HOWLING)
(HISSING)
(GASPS)
-(GROANS)
-(HISSES)
No!
No.
MAN: Follow me!
-You'll die for this.
-No. wait. it wasn't her!
(SOBBING)
We've got to leave.
They'll hang you for this.
Now.
I won't leave him.
You can't avenge him if you're dead.
MAN: Over there. go!
Not that way.
(MEN SHOUTING)
We need to go home.
-Loras.
-LITTLEFINGER: My lord. my lady.
Get out.
Stannis will be here in an hour.
When he arrives.
Renly's bannermen will flock to him.
Your former companions
will fight for the privilege
of selling you to their new king.
And you want that privilege for yourself.
You will note that I am standing here
talking to you.
not Stannis.
There's no time for this.
Ride back to Highgarden. sister.
I'm not running from Stannis.
Brienne of Tarth murdered Remy.
I don't believe that.
You don't believe that.
Who gained the most from our king's death?
Stannis.
I will put a sword through his righteous face.
You can't stay here.
He would have been a true king.
a good king.
LITTLEFINGER: Tell me. Ser Loras.
what do you desire most in this world?
Revenge.
I have always found that
to be the purest of motivations.
but you won't have a chance
to put your sword through Stannis.
not today.
You'll be cut to pieces
before he sets foot on solid ground.
If it is justice that you want. be smart about it.
You can't avenge him from the grave.
Bring the horses.
Please.
He was very handsome.
He was. Your Grace.
"Your Grace."
Calling yourself king doesn't make you one.
And if Renly wasn't a king. I wasn't a queen.
Do you want to be a queen?
No.
I want to be the queen.
(LAUGHING)
Killed? By Whom?
TYRION: Accounts differ.
Most seem to implicate CATELYN Stark
in some way.
Really? Who'd have thought?
Some say it was one of his own Kingsguard.
while still others say
it was Stannis himself who did it
after negotiations went sour.
Whomever did it. I say well done.
It's not what Varys says.
He says Renly's army
is flocking to support Stannis.
which would give Stannis superiority
over us on both land and sea.
LITTLEFINGER says we can
outspend him three to one.
And I say Father raised you
to have too much respect for money.
Stannis Baratheon is coming for us.
sooner rather than later.
Aren't there other things
you should be doing.
like sealing my daughter in a crate
so you can ship her away?
She'll be safer in Dome.
Yes. I know how concerned you are
for her safety.
It so happens that I am.
Myrcella is a sweet. innocent girl
and I don't blame her at all for you.
So clever.
Aren't you always so clever
with your schemes and your plots?
Schemes and plots are the same thing.
They are going to attack us.
We need to be ready.
No need to concern yourself over it.
The king is taking personal charge
of siege preparations.
May I ask specifically
what the king has in mind?
You may. specifically.
or you may ask vaguely.
The answer will be the same.
It's important that we talk about this.
It's the king's royal prerogative
to withhold sensitive information
from his councilors.
(DOOR CLOSES)
LANCEL: It's Wildfire.
Wildfire?
You wouldn't lie to me. would you. cousin?
-No.
-That's a lie right there.
It is not a lie. Why would I lie?
Tell me.
if the vile allegations
against my brother and sister are true.
do you think it will make Jaime
more likely to kill you or less likely?
When I tell him you're fucking her. I mean.
I'm telling you the truth.
The smart money would be on more likely.
She's making wildfire.
But then perhaps his own unnatural urges
will give him sympathy for yours.
The Alchemists' Guild
is being commissioned.
I suppose there's only one way to find out.
They have thousands of pots
already stored in their vaults.
They are planning to launch it
from the city walls
into Stannis' ships and armies.
Please.
When did she tell you this?
I heard her talking with the pyromancer.
And the other night. after I left her.
she went to meet him.
I swear to you.
Swear to me on what?
On my life.
But I don't care about your life.
In the light of the Seven.
by all that is holy and right.
I. LANCEL Lannister. do solemnly vow...
All right. all right. Enough.
Even torturing you is boring.
Just get out.
(GRUNTS)
Oh. LANCEL. tell my friend Bronn
to please kill you
if anything should happen to me.
Please kill me if anything
should happen to Lord Tyrion.
It will be my pleasure.
Your Grace.
What is it?
I'm sorry about your brother. Your Grace.
I wanted to let you know
that people grieve for him.
Fools love a fool.
I grieve for him as well. for the boy he was.
not the man he grew to be.
I need to speak to you
-about what I saw in that cave.
-I thought I made it clear to you
there'd be no need to speak to me
on this matter.
Your Grace. I...
I've never known you to need
to hear a thing twice.
And I've never known you
to hide from the truth.
You've come to lecture me on truth?
I've come to tell you that what I saw...
All my brother's bannermen
have come to my side.
Except the Tyrells. who fled like cowards.
They won't be able to resist us now.
Soon I shall be sitting on the Iron Throne.
Nothing is worth what this will cost you.
not even the Iron...
I'll hear no more about it.
MAN: Take a company of men.
secure the perimeter.
When do we sail for King's Landing?
As soon as I've consolidated my troops.
We'll make short work of the Lannisters' fleet.
Once Blackwater Bay is cleared.
we'll deliver our troops to their doorstep
and take the city.
And will you bring Lady Melisandre with you?
That's not your concern.
If you take King's Landing
with her by your side. the victory will be hers.
I never thought I'd have reason
to doubt your loyalty. Was I wrong?
Loyal service means telling hard truths.
Oh. truth again.
All right. what's the truth?
The hard truth?
She's a foreigner
preaching her foreign religion.
Some believe she whispers orders in your ear
and you obey.
What do you believe?
You won those bannermen from Renly.
Don't lose them to her.
We set out for King's Landing
without Lady Melisandre.
And you lead the fleet into Blackwater Bay.
Your Grace. I'm honored.
but my time on the sea
was spent evading ships. not attacking them.
The other lords won't be happy.
Most of those lords
should consider themselves lucky
I don't hang them for treason.
Hard truths cut both ways. Ser Davos.
GIRL: I've got it! I've got it!
MAN: So it's that one there at the top.
on the right.
Buy my fruit. my lord. Fresh fruit.
Stannis has more infantry.
more ships. more horses.
What do we have?
There's that mind of yours
you keep going on about.
Well. I've never actually been able
to kill people with it.
Good thing. I'd be out of a job.
What about your father?
He hasn't sent a raven in weeks.
He's very busy.
Being repeatedly humiliated by Robb Stark
is time-consuming.
We won't be able to
hold the city against Stannis.
not the way Jeffrey's planning on holding it.
MAN: Corruption.
CROWD: Yes!
We are swollen. bloated. foul.
Brother fornicates with sister
in the bed of kings
and we're surprised
when the fruit of their incest is rotten?
(CHEERING)
Yes. a rotten king.
It's hard to argue with his assessment.
Not after what he did to your birthday present.
The king is a lost cause.
It's the rest of us I'm worried about now.
A dancing king.
prancing down his bloodstained halls
to the tune of a twisted demon monkey.
(LAUGHING)
You have to admire his imagination.
He's talking about you.
What? Demon monkey?
People think you're pulling the king's strings.
They blame you for the city's ills.
Blame me? I'm trying to save them.
You don't need to convince me.
Demon monkey.
(MEN LAUGHING)
Yeah. come on.
THE ON: You're the crew of the Sea Bitch?
I'm your commander. Welcome.
Stop.
Stop!
Your captain commands you to stop!
Where are we headed. Captain?
The Stony Shore. to raid their villages.
There'll be spoils in it for you. and women.
if you do your jobs well.
And who decides if we've done our jobs well?
I do.
Your captain.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I have been reaving and raping
since before you left Baton's balls. Captain.
Don't reckon I've got much use
for your ideas on how to do it.
for a captain at all.
I'm thinking I can do the job of captain
real well myself.
All I need is a ship.
You wouldn't know where I could
find myself a ship now. would you?
You could do that.
take the ship. head out on your own.
And I will hunt you down. drag you back here
in chains and hang you for a traitor.
Stop. We yield.
Congratulations on your first command.
Thank you. Kind of you to come see me off.
Oh. I'm not here for you.
I was just on my way to Red Harbor.
I've got 30 ships.
There's nowhere to put them here.
Too narrow.
You'd better get out there.
Wouldn't want her to set sail without you.
That would never happen.
My crew would wait on deck
for a year if I asked them to.
This lot. though...
Enjoy the Stony Shore.
Come on. I'll take you out.
Who are you?
Dagmer. your first mate.
Why aren't you with the rest of them?
Or did they send you to row me out
and dump me halfway in the sea?
That would be good for a laugh.
They're not gonna respect you
until you prove yourself.
And how am I supposed to prove myself
by pillaging piss-poor fishing villages?
You're not.
And yet that's the task my father has given me
to prove that I'm a true Iron Islander.
They're all Iron Islanders.
Do they do as they're told
or do they do as they like?
THE ON: The Stony Shore's not far
from Torrhen's Square.
The seat of the House of Tallhart.
a more impressive prize
than a few fishermen's daughters.
-What. you don't think we could take it?
-No. we could.
We could never hold it
for more than a few days.
As soon as Winterfell got word
that we'd taken Torrhen's Square.
the Starks would send their men
to take it back.
And then...
Take me to my ship.
The Starks have overextended their lines.
Now that summer's over.
they'll have a hard time
keeping their men and horses fed.
The Starks understand winter
better than we ever will.
The cold won't beat them.
Our spies report growing discontent
among the Northern lords.
They want to return home
and gather the harvest before the crops turn.
And I'm sure if those same spies
snuck into our own encampments.
they would report growing discontent
amongst the Southern lords.
This is war. no one's content.
We've underestimated
the Stark boy for too long.
He has a good mind for warfare.
his men worship him.
And as long as he keeps winning battles.
they'll keep believing he is King in the North.
You've been waiting for him to fail.
He is not going to fail. not without our help.
So how do we stop him?
REGINALD: We've worked
through the night. my lord.
Perhaps we'd profit from some sleep.
Yes. I think you would. Reginald.
And because you're my cousin.
I might even let you wake from that sleep.
Go. I'm sure your wife must miss you.
My wife's in Lannisport.
Well. then you'd better start riding.
Go. before I change my mind
and send her your head.
If your name wasn't Lannister.
you'd be scrubbing out pots
in the cook's tent. Go!
Not wine. water.
We'll be here for some time.
Girl.
Where are you from?
Maidenpool. my lord.
And who are the Lords of Maidenpool?
Remind me.
House Mooton. my lord.
And what is their sigil?
A red salmon.
I think a Maidenpool girl
would remember that.
You're a Northerner. aren't you?
Good. One more time. where are you from?
Barrowton. my lord.
House Dustin.
Two crossed longaxes beneath a black crown.
And what do they say
of Robb Stark in the North?
They call him the Young Wolf.
And?
They say he rides into battle
on the back of a giant dire wolf.
They say he can turn into
a wolf himself when he wants.
They say he can't be killed.
And do you believe them?
No. my lord.
Anyone can be killed.
Fetch that water.
A girl says nothing.
A girl keeps her mouth closed.
No one hears.
and friends may talk in secret. yes?
A boy becomes a girl.
I was always a girl.
And I was always aware.
But the girl keeps secrets.
It is not for a man to spoil them.
You're one of them now.
I should have let you burn.
And you fetch water for one of them now.
Why is this right for you and wrong for me?
-I didn't have a choice.
-You did.
I did.
And here we are.
A man pays his debts.
A man owes three.
Three what?
The Red God takes what is his. lovely girl.
And only death may pay for life.
You saved me and the two I was with.
You stole three deaths from the Red God.
We have to give them back.
Speak three names
and the man will do the rest.
Three lives I will give you.
no more. no less.
and we're done.
I can name anyone
and you'll kill him?
A man has said.
The one who tortures everyone.
A man needs a name.
I don't know his name.
They call him the Tickler.
That is enough.
Go now. girl. Your master is thirsty.
MORMONT: He's not here yet.
He'd have seen us. blown the horn.
JON: When will he come?
The Half hand does things in his own time.
My uncle told me stories about him.
Most of them are true.
I heard the Half hand
spent half of last winter beyond the Wall.
The whole winter.
He was north of the Skirting Pass
when the snows came.
Had to wait for the thaw.
So it is possible for someone
to survive out here on their own.
Well. possible for the Half hand.
Beautiful. isn't it?
Gilly would love it here.
There's nothing more sickening
than a man in love.
(MAN CHATTERING)
MAN: About time you did something.
At least you'll keep warm.
The Fist of the First Men.
Think of how old this place is.
Before the Targaryens defeated the Andals.
before the Andals took Westeros
from the First Men.
Before I die. please. stop talking.
Thousands and thousands of years ago.
the First Men stood here where we're standing
all through the long night.
What do you think they were like.
the First Men?
Stupid.
Smart people don't find themselves
in places like this.
I think they were afraid.
I think they came here
to get away from something.
And I don't think it worked.
(HORN SOUNDING)
Wildlings?
JON: One blast is for rangers returning.
Wildlings is two blasts.
So you got to stand there waiting.
wondering.
One blast for friends.
two for foes.
And three for White Walkers.
It's been a thousand years.
but that's the only time
they blow the horn three times.
But if it's been a thousand years.
how do you know?
-Well...
-BOTH: I read it in a book.
Look.
It's Qhorin Half hand.
Aye. we'll live another day.
Hurrah.
Take care. my lord.
I remember reading an old sailors' proverb.
"Piss on wildfire and your cock burns off."
Oh. I have not conducted this experiment.
It could well be true.
The substance burns so hot.
it melts wood. stone. even steel.
and. of course. flesh.
The substance burns so hot.
it melts flesh like tallow.
After the dragons died. wildfire was the key
to the Targaryen power.
(BRONN SCOFFS)
My companion takes issue.
If I could tell you how many crazy old men
I've seen pushing carts around army camps
making grand claims
about jars full of pig shit.
-No offense meant.
-Our order does not deal in pig shit.
The substance is fire given form.
And we have been perfecting it
since the days of Maegor.
To do what?
The jars are put in catapults
and flung at the enemy.
How much do you have?
If you could get real soldiers
to man the catapults.
then maybe you'd hit
your target one time in ten.
but all the real soldiers
are in the Riverlands with your father.
My lord. this man is insulting.
I don't know if you've ever seen a battle.
old man.
but things can get a bit messy.
'Cause when we're flinging things at Stannis.
he's flinging them right back at us.
Men die. men shit themselves. men run.
which means pots falling.
which means fire inside the walls.
which means the poor cunts trying to defend
the city end up burning it down.
My friend remains unconvinced.
He would not dare insult my order
whilst Aerys Targaryen lived.
Well. he's not living anymore.
And all his pots of wildfire
didn't help him. did they?
Men win wars. not magic tricks.
We have been working tirelessly.
day and night.
ever since your royal sister
commanded us to do so.
Our present count stands at 7.811.
Enough to burn Stannis Baratheon's fleet
and armies both.
This is a shit idea.
I'm afraid I have to concur
with my advisor. Wisdom Hallyne.
The contents of this room
could lay King's Landing low.
You won't be making wildfire
for my sister any longer.
You'll be making it for me.
-(DRAGON CHITTERS)
-(SPEAKING HIGH VALYRIAN)
(SQUEAKS)
(SPEAKING HIGH VALYRIAN)
(HISSES)
(SCREECHES)
(CHUCKLES)
He'll be able to feed himself from now on.
Let him sleep. Doreah.
Yes. Khaleesi.
He loves you.
I rewove this part of the top.
And I fixed the heel on this one.
Thank you. my friend.
Did you see the dress Xaro had made for you?
They say he's the wealthiest man in Qarth.
It is known.
And if Qarth is the wealthiest city in Essos...
The last time a rich man gave me a dress.
he was selling me to Khal Drogo.
May he ride forever through the night lands.
Xaro is our host.
but we know nothing about him.
Men like to talk about other men
when they're happy.
You would look like a real princess
in Xaro's...
She's not a princess. She's a Khaleesi.
You should wear it. Khaleesi.
You are their guest. It would be rude not to.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
-(PEOPLE CHATTING)
-(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
And you must visit the night market.
The Qartheen night market
is like no night market you've ever seen.
It sounds wonderful.
The Meereenis think they have a night market.
I will take you there myself.
Please excuse me for a moment.
(MEN SPEAKING DOTHRAKI)
What are they doing?
Malakko says the statue is too heavy to carry.
Kovarro says that Malakko is an idiot.
They can pry out the gems.
the rest is pure gold.
Very soft.
He can chop off as much as we can carry.
Or melt it. Very simple.
We are his guests!
You can't pry it or chop it or melt it.
Of course not. Khaleesi!
We will wait until we leave.
Not even when we leave.
Why not?
Our host saved us from the
Red Waste and you want to steal from him?
I will hear no more.
My brother used to say
the only thing the Dothraki knew how to do
was steal things better men have built.
It's not the only thing.
They're quite good at killing the better men.
That's not the kind of queen I'm going to be.
PYAT PREE: Mother of Dragons.
On behalf of the warlocks of Qarth.
I welcome you.
A demonstration?
Take this gem.
Look at it.
Into its depths.
So many facets.
Look closely enough
and you can see yourself in them.
Often more than once.
Should you grow tired
of Xaro's baubles and trinkets.
it would be an honor
to host you at the House of the Undying.
You are always welcome. Mother of Dragons.
(GUESTS APPLAUDING)
My apologies.
Pyat Pree is one of the Thirteen.
It was customary for me
to extend him an invitation.
Customs die slow deaths in Qarth.
What is the House of the Undying?
It is where the warlocks go
to squint at dusty books
and drink shade of the evening.
It turns their lips blue and their minds soft.
So soft. they actually believe
their parlor tricks are magic.
WOMAN: You watch over her.
Do I know you?
I know you.
Jorah MORMONT of Bear Island.
Who are you?
I'm no one.
But she is the Mother of Dragons.
She needs true protectors.
now more than ever.
They shall come day and night
to see the wonder born into the world again.
And when they see. they shall lust.
for dragons are fire made flesh.
And fire is power.
It looked like Stannis.
To me it just looked like...
A shadow in the shape of a man.
In the shape of Stannis.
We should reach my son's camp tomorrow.
Will you stay there long. my lady?
Only long enough
to tell Robb what I have seen.
After that. I will leave for Winterfell.
My two youngest need me.
I've been away from them for far too long.
I never knew my mother.
I'm sorry.
My own mother died on the birthing bed
when I was very young.
It's a bloody business.
What comes after is even harder.
Once you're safely back
amongst your own people.
will you give me leave to go. my lady?
You mean to kill Stannis.
I swore a vow.
But Stannis has a great army around him.
His own guards are sworn to keep him safe.
I'm as good as any of them.
I should never have fled.
Renly's death was no fault of yours.
You served him bravely.
I only held him that once
as he was dying.
He's gone. Brienne.
You serve nothing and no one
by following him into the earth.
Renly's enemies are Robb's enemies as well.
I do not know your son. my lady.
But I could serve you. if you would have me.
You have courage.
Not battle courage. perhaps.
but. I don't know.
a woman's kind of courage.
And I think that when the time comes.
you will not hold me back.
Promise me that you will not hold me back
from Stannis.
When the time comes.
I will not hold you back.
Then I am yours. my lady.
I will shield your back
and give my life for yours. if it comes to that.
I swear it by the Old Gods and the new.
I vow that you shall always
have a place in my home
and at my table
and that I shall ask no service of you
that might bring you dishonor.
I swear it by the Old Gods and the new.
(THUDS)
MAN: And it's not just thieves. my lord.
There's wolves in them hills now.
more than I ever seen.
They come down in the night
and they kill my sheep.
My three sons is away
fighting for your brother. my lord.
They'll fight. keep fighting
till they're told to go home.
I have no one to man my flock now. Only me.
I can't keep watch all day and all night.
We can send two orphan boys
from Winterstown home with you
to help watch over your flock
if you can give them room and board.
My wife always prayed for more children.
We'll look after them. Thank you. my lord.
And may the gods bless you and yours.
Stop it.
If that's everyone.
I'm going to go for a ride before dark.
-Good.
-Hodor.
-Ah! Lord Stark.
Torrhen's Square is under siege.
Torrhen's Square
is barely 40 leagues from here.
How can the Lannisters strike so far north?
Might be a raiding party led by the mountain.
Might be sell swords paid by Tywin Lannister.
We have to help them.
Most of the fighting men are away with Robb.
but I can gather 200 decent men.
Do you need so many?
If we can't protect our own bannermen.
why should they protect us?
Go. Ser Rodrik. Take the men you need.
Won't take long. my lord.
Southerners don't do well up here.
-(BIRD SQUAWKS)
-BRAN: So. what does it mean?
Ask your Maester Luwin.
He's the one studying books all the time.
I did ask him.
He'd never heard of a three-eyed raven.
Must not mean anything. then.
You're lying.
You might be a little lord.
but don't you call me a liar.
-You know what it means.
-I never said I didn't.
You didn't give me an honest answer.
That's not the same as being a liar.
Well. it's not far off.
So. you've been dreaming
of a three-eyed raven again?
In the gods wood.
you told me you didn't dream.
Now who's a liar?
What did you see in your dream?
Something bad?
Tell me. boy.
I dreamt that the sea came to Winterfell.
I saw waves crashing against the gates
and the water came flowing over the walls...
It flooded the castle.
Drowned men were floating here.
in the yard.
Ser Rodrik was one of them.
The sea is hundreds of miles away.
I know.
-It's just a stupid dream.
-I've got to get these potatoes to the kitchen.
Otherwise they'll put me in chains again.
Osha.
The three-eyed raven.
what do they say about it north of the Wall?
They say all sorts of crazy things
north of the Wall.
-(WIND HOWLING)
-(HORSES NEIGHING)
QHORIN: There.
MORMONT: Where?
On that mountain.
SAMWELL: I don't see very well.
JON: A fire.
There's a fire.
The people sitting around it
have better eyes than yours or mine.
When they see us coming.
that fire becomes a signal.
Gives Mance Rayder plenty of time
to throw a party in our honor.
How many wildlings have joined him?
From what we can tell. all of them.
Mance has gathered them all
like deer against the wolves.
They're almost ready to make their move.
-Where?
-Somewhere safe.
Somewhere south.
Can't just march into their midst.
And we can't wait for them here with nothing
but a pile of stones to protect us.
You saying we should fall back to the Wall?
Mance was one of us once.
Now he's one of them.
He's going to teach them
our way of doing things.
They'll hit us in force
and they won't run away when we hit back.
They're gonna be more organized than before.
more disciplined.
more like us.
So we need to be more like them.
do things their way.
Sneak in. kill Mance.
and scatter them to the winds
before they can march on the Wall.
-And to do that...
-We need to get rid of those lookouts.
It's not a job for 400 men.
I need to move fast and silent.
Hawker. Stonesnake. Borba.
Lord Commander. I'd like to join Lord Qhorin.
I've been called lots of things.
but that might be my first Lord Qhorin.
(LAUGHING)
You're a steward. Snow. not a ranger.
I've fought and killed a Wight.
How many rangers can say that?
He's the one?
Aye. You killed a Wight.
You also let an old man beat you bloody
and take your sword.
(ALL LAUGHING)
QHORIN: Craster?
In the boy's defense. that's a tough old goat.
I could take up Jon's duties
while he's gone. my lord.
It would be no trouble.
Well. I hope you make a better ranger
than you do a steward.
Go on.
XARO: So. tell me.
how long has your manservant
been in love with you?
He's not my manservant
and he's not in love with me.
He's my advisor.
my friend.
Unlikely.
I can almost always tell what a man wants.
And what about what a woman wants?
Much more complicated.
You. for example. what do you want?
To cross the Narrow Sea
and take back the Iron Throne.
Why?
Because I promised my khalasar
I'd protect them
-and find them a safe home.
-(CHUCKLES)
You want to conquer
the Seven Kingdoms for the Dothraki?
I want them because they're mine by right.
The Iron Throne is mine and I will take it.
Ah. a conqueror.
And how did you get all of this?
Did someone give it to you?
No. I come from nothing.
I hit the docks like a piece of cargo.
except someone normally cares
what happens to cargo.
So you wanted more than you had
and you took it.
You're a conqueror. too.
You're just less ambitious.
(CHUCKLES)
What do you want. Xaro Xhoan Daxos?
At the gates of the city. you bled for me.
Why?
I will show you why.
The door and the vault
is made of VALYRIAN stone.
The hardest steel does not make a mark.
I offered the greatest locksmiths in Qarth
their weight in gold if they could break into it.
I made the same offer to the greatest thieves.
They all went home empty-handed.
The only thing that can open this door
is this key.
And behind the door?
(XARO CHUCKLES)
And it can all be mine?
All? Let us say half.
More than enough
to buy horses. ships. armies...
Enough to go home.
All I have to do?
Is marry me.
That was a romantic proposal.
I've already married once for love.
but the gods stole her from me.
I come from nothing.
My mother and father
never owned a pair of shoes.
But marry me.
and I will give you the Seven Kingdoms
and our children
will be princes and princesses.
See?
I have more ambition than you thought.
The time is right.
Daenerys Targaryen. First of Your Name.
Robert Baratheon is dead.
JORAH: If you cross the sea
with an army you bought...
The Seven Kingdoms
are at war with one another.
Four false kings destroying the country.
To win Westeros.
you need support from Westeros.
The usurper is dead.
The Starks fight the Lannisters.
and Baratheons fight each other.
According to your new friend
who earned your trust by cutting his hand?
The time to strike is now.
We need to find ships and an army
or we'll spend the rest of our lives
rotting away at the edge of the world.
Rich men do not become rich
by giving more than they get.
They'll give you ships and soldiers
and they'll own you forever.
Moving carefully is the hard way.
but it's the right way.
And if I'd listened to that advice
outside the gates of Qarth.
we'd all be dead by now.
I know the opportunity before you
seems like the last you'll ever have.
-but you must...
-Do not speak to me like I'm a child.
-I only want...
-What do you want?
Tell me.
-To see you on the Iron Throne.
-Why?
You have a good claim.
A title. A birthright.
But you have something more than that.
You may cover it up and deny it.
but you have a gentle heart.
You would not only be respected and feared.
you would be loved.
Someone who can rule and should rule.
Centuries come and go without
a person like that coming into the world.
There are times when I look at you
and I still can't believe you're real.
So what would you have me do.
as my advisor?
Make your own way.
Find your own ship. You only need one.
The allies we need are in Westeros. not Qarth.
And how do I get the ship?
I'll find it for you.
A sound ship with a good captain.
I look forward to meeting him.
Khaleesi.
(DRAGONS CHIRPING)
(WATER SIZZLING)
You should stand side face.
Sideface?
Sideways.
Why?
Smaller target.
Am I fighting someone?
You're practicing for a fight.
You should practice right.
-(LOUD THUD)
-(WOMAN SCREAMING)
MAN: Guards!
Did you see anything?
Go up there. Go and see where he fell from.
Go up the battlement.
Move away.
Stand back. He's dead.